martin-audio.com 2019-04-26

# Privacy Policy - Terms and Conditions from Martin Audio

### At Martin Audio we’re committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

If you share your contact details with us it’s important that you understand how this is used and how you can control its usage, in compliance with General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

1 Customer Accounts  
2 Signed Up for Ongoing News  
3 General Enquires, Event Sign Up or Software Registration  
4 Website Users  
5 IP Address Lookup  
6 How to Control Your Personal Data  
7 Website Terms and Conditions  
8 Cookies

#### Collection and Usage of Personal Data

##### Customer Accounts

If you have a customer account, Martin Audio Ltd may require personal information in order to manage your account or to provide you with access to its services. Any such information will be used exclusively by Martin Audio, our employees, suppliers, agents and any applicable third party service providers required to set up your service or needed to respond to your requests. This data is held within Martin Audio’s ERP database, while email addresses alongside correspondence is also retained within the Company’s Outlook email service.

If you are a distributor, reseller or rental company and have consented to have your company details published on our website for referral and promotional purposes these can be found [here](https://martin-audio.com/where-to-buy). 

* * *

Back to top

* * *

##### Signed Up for Ongoing News

If you have given us consent to contact you with breaking news, product information and event details straight to your email inbox, that consent will be recorded (including Name, Permission Statement, Date, Time, IP address) and you can expect to receive no more than a weekly email bulletin. Equally, you will be able to unsubscribe at any time.

If you have consented for email bulletins then it is important that you understand we utilise [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/ "Mailchimp") for our marketing database and email service for the following purposes: 

  * __The transfer of contact information to MailChimp
  *  __To store contact information in our MailChimp account
  *  __To send you marketing emails from our MailChimp account

However, your email address and details will **NOT** be shared with any other Third-Party for marketing purposes. 

* * *

Back to top

* * *

##### General Enquires, Event Sign Up or Software Registration

Any enquiry via the website where personal information is shared will only be used to provide the services or information you have requested from us. Such data is held on Martin Audio servers. You will also be given the additional option to opt in for ongoing news at that point. (See Above). 

* * *

Back to top

* * *

##### Website Users

While visiting this website, Martin Audio Ltd's computer servers may gather non-personal information ("cookies") for the purposes of statistical and market research. A cookie has been described as a piece of data stored on your computer containing information about you. The information obtained from your cookies will be used for the purposes of updating and improving this website. Such information may include, without limitation, the type of browser you are using, the domain name you came from, and other non-personal information.

We use Google Analytics to store information about how visitors use our website so that we may make improvements and give visitors a better user experience.  
Google Analytics is a third-party information storage system that records information about the pages you visit, the length of time you were on specific pages and the website in general, how you arrived at the site and what you clicked on when you were there. These cookies do not store any personal information about you eg name, address etc and we do not share the data. You can view their privacy policy below:

Google - <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

Throughout this website there are links to external sites not under the control of Martin Audio Ltd. Therefore, Martin Audio Ltd is not responsible for the content, use or misuse, or privacy policy of any such linked site not controlled by Martin Audio Ltd. Martin Audio Ltd provides these links solely for your convenience and we reserve the right to cancel or discontinue any link at any time.

#####  **IP address lookup**

Our website also deploys IP identification and IP tracking software via the [GatorLeads](https://www.communigator.co.uk/) service. When you visit our website your IP address will be recorded. This address will be matched against public and proprietary IP address databases to provide us with information about your visit. This information may identify the organisation to whom the IP address is registered but not individuals. In some limited cases i.e. single person companies, it may be possible to identify personal data from publicly available ICANN data.

This information is used explicitly to profile website visitors in order to better understand the way in which our website content is viewed by different target segments and companies of the professional audio industry and as it relates to the services provided and needs of end users and venues. It is also used, for example, to identify the types of organisations that might be interested in demonstrations of our audio equipment, project design service or training needs. 

##### How to Control Your Personal Data

Everyone has the right to ask for details about the way we use their personal data and can ask to do certain things with that data.

You can request that personal data be corrected or completed, transferred to another organisation, prohibited for certain uses, or removed completely—all in a timely manner.

If you have any concerns, queries, or changes that need to be made regarding your personal data, you can do so by emailing [marketing@martin-audio.com](mailto:marketing@martin-audio.com) or contacting our [UK office](https://martin-audio.com/contacts/uk). 

* * *

Back to top

* * *

##### Website Terms and Conditions

If you continue to browse and use this website you are agreeing to comply with and be bound by the following terms and conditions of use, which together with our privacy policy govern Martin Audio Ltd's relationship with you in relation to this website.

The term "Martin Audio Ltd" or "us" or "we" refers to the owner of the website. The term "you" refers to the user or viewer of our website.

The use of this website is subject to the following terms of use:

The content of the pages of this website is for your general information and use only. It is subject to change without notice.

Neither we nor any third parties provide any warranty or guarantee as to the accuracy, timeliness, performance, completeness or suitability of the information and materials found or offered on this website for any particular purpose. You acknowledge that such information and materials may contain inaccuracies or errors and we expressly exclude liability for any such inaccuracies or errors to the fullest extent permitted by law.

Your use of any information or materials on this website is entirely at your own risk, for which we shall not be liable. It shall be your own responsibility to ensure that any products, services or information available through this website meet your specific requirements.

Unauthorised use of this website may give rise to a claim for damages and/or be a criminal offence.

From time to time this website may also include links to other websites. These links are provided for your convenience to provide further information. They do not signify that we endorse the website(s). We have no responsibility for the content of the linked website(s).

Your use of this website and any dispute arising out of such use of the website is subject to the laws of England and Wales. 

* * *

Back to top

* * *

##### Cookies

This section describes use of cookies and other technologies.

A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer, mobile phone, or other device when you visit a website. The cookie will help website providers to recognise your device the next time you visit their website. There are other similar technologies such as pixel tags (transparent graphic images placed on a web page or in an email, which indicate that a page or email has been viewed), web bugs (similar to pixel tags), and web storage, which are used in desktop software or mobile devices.

We use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your device for a set period of time or until you delete them). We use the following types of cookies for the purposes explained in this chart:

Essential Operational| 

These cookies are necessary to allow us to operate as you have requested. For example, they let us recognise what type of subscriber you are and then provide you with services accordingly.   
  
---|---  
Performance / Analytics| 

We use these cookies to analyse how the Martin Audio Website is accessed, is used, or is performing. We use this information to maintain, operate, and continually improve the our website. We may also obtain information from our email newsletters, including whether you opened or forwarded a newsletter or clicked on any of its content. This information tells us about our newsletters' effectiveness and helps us ensure that we're delivering information that you find interesting.   
  
Functional| 

These cookies let us operate certain functions of the Website in line with the choices you make. These cookies mean that when you continue to use or come back to the website, we can provide you with our services as you have asked for them to be provided, such as knowing your username, remembering how you have customised our services.   
  
* * *

Back to top

* * *
